Finding Aid for Edith Gomberg Papers, 1940-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Research
  - Alcoholism in women studies
    - Alcoholism in women: psycho-social aspects
      - Data
        - Consequences of drinking, 2 folders (Box 11)
        - Demographics of subjects (Box 11)
        - Early drinking behaviors-pre-onset (Box 11)
        - Early life, family of origin (Box 11)
        - Psychiatric symptoms (Box 11)
      - Results (transparencies), 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Raw data
        [CR RESTRICTED until 2082 ]
        - Interviews 0001-0040, 4 folders (Box 12)
          [CR RESTRICTED until July 1 2082 ]
        - Interviews 0041-0080, 4 folders (Box 13)
        - Interviews 0081-0120, 4 folders (Box 14)
        - Interviews 0121-0160, 4 folders (Box 15)
        - Interviews 0161-0200, 4 folders (Box 16)
        - Interviews 0201-0240, 4 folders (Box 17)
        - Interviews 0241-0280, 4 folders (Box 18)
        - Interviews 0281-1020, 4 folders (Box 19)
        - Interviews 1021-1060, 4 folders (Box 20)
        - Interviews 1061-1100, 4 folders (Box 21)
        - Interviews 1101-1137, 4 folders (Box 22)
        - Interviews (Box 23)
          - Drafts (Box 23)
          - Unlogged (Box 23)
    - ???? Coping of daughters in alcoholic and nonalcoholic families, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
- Audiovisual Material
  The Audiovisual Material (0.3 linear ft., 1977-1988 and undated) contains photographs and audiocassettes. Researchers will find photographs of Gomberg with various individuals as well as group photos of the Department of Psychiatry and the Alcohol Research Center at the University of Michigan. Audiocassettes cover Gomberg's research, with topics detailed in the finding aid.
  - Photographs (Box 24)
  - Sound recordings
    - Access, Indianapolis, IN
      - The woman alcoholic, undated (Box 24)
    - Biomonitoring Applications, Inc.
      - Women problem drinkers: treatment considerations, 1977; 2 audiocassettes (Box 24)
        (Tape T 47)
    - EMC, Annenberg Center for Health Sciences
      - Women are still underserved, February 16, 1988 (Box 24)
        (88-A129-05)
      - Should treatment units be separate?, February 16, 1988; 2 audiocassettes (Box 24)
        (88-A129-07)
    - Jack Quigley
      - Oregon Institute of Alcohol Studies, 1985 (Box 24)